Joseph McDonald Collection of Plastics Patents
Joseph McDonald Collection of Plastics Patents
1930-1989
McDonald, Joseph.
1 linear ft.
Collection contains copies of patents for plastic food and beverage containers collected by Joseph McDonald from 1951 to 1989, in the course of his work for Sweetheart Plastics, Inc. and a selection of technical offprints and reports.
2663588
Biographical History
Joseph McDonald was an American researcher and consultant in the field of plastics. He was employed by Sweetheart Plastics, Inc., a division of Maryland Cup Corporation, in Wilmington, Massachusetts. He later formed Joseph McDonald Associates, Inc. in Lexington, Massachusetts.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Joseph McDonald Collection of Plastics Patents contains copies of patents for plastic food and beverage containers collected by Joseph McDonald from 1951 to 1989, in the course of his work for Sweetheart Plastics, Inc. (originally Maryland Cup) and a selection of technical offprints and reports. Many of these patents are the work of Thomas W. Winstead who head the research division of Sweetheart.
Patents contains copies of patents for plastic food and beverage containers. Notes and letters regarding work and research on products and patents by Sweetheart Plastics are kept with the patents they describe. These patents originate mostly from the United States Patent Office but include one Canadian and one German patent.
Publications contains articles, papers, and reports about plastics and its applications, including electrical insulating, styrene and packaging. It contains two reports written for Sweetheart Plastics relating to extrusion and thermoforming technical data (1966) and two reports written for Winstead Patents, a division of Maryland Corp. (1977 and 1989).
Arrangement of the Collection
Collection found in archives intact in a largely chronological order. Notes and letters were kept with patents as found to preserve original order and context as much as possible.
Related Material
has numerous holdings in the areas of plastics and industrial design. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Plastics; McDonald, Joseph.; Winstead, Thomas W.; Sweetheart Plastics, Inc.; Maryland Cup Corporation.; Dow Chemical Company.; United States. -- Patent Office.; Plastics industry and trade.; Patents.; Beverage containers.; Food containers.; Plastic containers.; Plastics -- Extrusion.; Plastics in packaging.; Styrene.; Thermoplastics.; Plastics machinery.; Correspondence.; Notes (documents); Reports.; Patents.; Engineers.; Inventors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Transfer from National Plastics Center and Museum, 2008.
Inventory
- Patents
  - Correspondence, notes, etc., 1951; 1986,; 1989 (Box 1)
    Notes on a Discussion of New Polystyrene Materials; J.L. Amos, C. Miller, W.H. Schuette, E.L. Kropscott, H.W. Wehr and J.N. McDonald; October 15, 1951
    Application of Frederick W. Gander, Erhard F. Hoegger and William P. Kane; To The United States Patent Office; Polyethylene, terephthalate/terpolymer blends; Films, sheets and articles made using such blends; and Method of making trays using such sheets
    Receipt from Office of Patent and Trademark Services; To Patent and Trademark Customer Joseph McDonald Associates, Inc.; May 12, 1989
    Letter from Herbert L. Gatewood of Marullo & Barnes, Attorneys at Law, Boston, MA; To Mr. Gerald K. Parker, President of Artisan Plastics Corporation; Subject: Re: Tamper Evident Package Invention, File No. 3353/3.86; August 4, 1986
    Letter from Du Pont Corporation, E.W. Heiderich; To Gim P. Fong, Sweethearts Plastic, Inc.; December 13, 1977
  - Patents, 1930-1966 (Box 1)
    Container, Henry Nias and William Poster, inventors; Lily-Tulip Cup Corporation; June 24, 1930; patent # 1,766,226
    Method of and Apparatus for Producing Reticulated Articles from Thermoplastics, John J. Grebe and Ernest H. Harder, inventors; The Dow Chemical Company; October 31, 1944; patent # 2,361,369
    Vinylidene Chloride Compositions, Edgar C. Britton and Harold W. Moll, inventors; The Dow Chemical Company; Sept 18, 1945; patent # 2,384,884
    Foamed Polystyrene Article, James B. Sisson, inventor; St. Regis Paper Company; December 15, 1959; patent # 2,917,217
    Process for Producing Folded Rim on a Container of Plastic Material, as well as an apparatus for carrying out this process, Kornelis van de Kerke and Dirk van de Kerke, inventors; July 11, 1961; patent # 2,991,602
    Method for Cold Forming Plastic Article, Eckel R. Lane; inventor; March 30, 1976; patent # 3,947,539
    Extruded Foam Polystyrene, Albert R. Kudlach; inventor; September 18, 1962; patent # 648, 802
    Thin Walled Plastic Container, James R. Caine, inventor; July 24, 1962; patent #3,045,887
    Storage stable expandable polymeric composition containing expandable polymeric particles and two different blowing agents and method of making same, Carl H. Pottenger, inventor; Koppers Company, Inc.; patent # 3,089,857
    Cup for hot beverage, William L. Miller, inventor; Continental Can Company, Inc.; May 3, 1964; patent # 3,123,273
    Composite Plastic Container, Albert McConnell, inventor; Scott Paper Company; August 10, 1965; patent # 3,199,757
    Container Rim Formation, Andre F. Commeyras, inventor; Sweetheart Plastics, Inc.; December 13, 1966; patent # 3,291,361
    Plastic container for dairy products or the like, Paul Davis, inventor; Sweetheart Plastics, Inc.; March 29, 1966; Patent # 204,212
    Nestable Container, Samuel Shapiro and James C. White, inventors; American Seal-Kap Corp.; November 29. 1966; patent # 3,288,340
  - Patents, 1967-1970 (Box 1)
    Combined Paperboard and Plastic Egg Carton, Theodore C. Baker, inventor; October 10, 1967; patent # 3,346,171
    Container Lip Rolling Machine, Walter O. Weber, inventor; Haveg Industries, Inc.; December 19, 1967; patent # 3,358,331
    Automatic Rim Rolling Apparatus, Frank Rukavina, inventor; Illinois Tool Works, Inc.; July 6, 1965; patent # 3,192,565
    Method of extruding a foamed plastic sheet having a skin on one surface, Jerome Alfred Cherney, Hubert Joseph Germiat and Elbert William Perry, inventors; American Can Company; March 28, 1967; patent # 3,311,681
    Nestable Containers, Daniel R. Kalata and Henry H. Houston, inventors; October 17, 1967; patent # 3,347,411
    Nesting Container, Martin Mueller, inventor; Lily-Tulip Cup Corporation; December 19, 1967; patent # 3,358,879
    Container, Charles Fitzgerald, inventor, The Dow Chemical Company; August 12, 1968, patent # 3,396,868
    Plastic Glasses, Paul K. Schilling, inventor; Plastics, Inc.; January 16, 1968; patent # 3,363,820Package for Fragile Articles, Bryant Edwards, inventor; Illinois Tool Works, Inc.; February 3, 1970; patent # 3,493,164
    Insulated Double Cup, Bryant Edwards, inventor; Illinois Tool Works, Inc.; March 12, 1968; Patent # 3,372,830
    Plastic container for materials in bulk, Stephen Fotos, inventor; Union Carbide Corporation; January 9, 1968; Patent # 3,362,575
    Container Lid, Robert J. McCormick, inventor; The Dow Chemical Company; January 9, 1968; Patent # 3,362,565
    Method for printing on foam polystyrene with cellulose ether printing composition, Ralph Karsten, inventor; Screen-Flock Industries, Inc.; July 29, 1969; Patent # 3,458,340
    Kunststoffbehalter, Antrag auf Nichtnennung, inventor; Tedeco-Verpackung; October 16, 1969; Patent # 1,302,048
    Extrusion Method, Lloyd Edward Lefevre and Peter Breidt, Jr., inventors; The Dow Chemical Company; November 18, 1969; Patent # 3,479,425
    Method of Extruding Laminates, Douglas S. Chisholm and Walter J. Schrenk, inventors; The Dow Chemical Company; January 19, 1971; patent # 3,557,265
    Apparatus for Extrusion of Thermoplastics, Gene Leroy, inventor; Union Carbide Corporation; December 30, 1969; Patent # 3,486,192
    Apparatus for Extruding Thermoplastic Materials, J.S. Gwinn and D.C. Christensen, inventors; Phillips Petroleum Company; December 30, 1969; Patent # 3,486,193
    Continuous method and apparatus for manufacturing articles from foamed thermoplastic material, Thomas W. Winstead, inventor; November 25, 1969; Patent # 3,479,694
    Biaxial Stretching Machine, H.C. Tsien, inventor; Esso Research and Engineering Company; February 18, 1969; Patent # 3,427,684
    Biaxial Orientation, Heinz E. Pahlke, inventor; July 15, 1969; Patent # 3,456,044
    Thermoforming Apparatus, Joseph C. Morin, inventor; Cupples Container Company; October 21, 1969; Patent # 3,473,195
    Container, James E. Foote, inventor; Diamond International Corporation; September 23, 1969; Patent # 3, 468,468
    Extruder for Shaping Powdery Thermoplastic Resins; Akira Iwata and Sadao Murai, inventors; Sekisui Kazaku Kogyo Kabushiki Kaisha; October 7, 1969; Patent # 3,470,584
    Deep Draw Article Forming Apparatus, Bryant Edwards, inventor; Illinois Tool Works, Inc.; May 12, 1970; Patent # 3,510,913
    Method for the Preparation of Foamed Sheet and Product Obtained Thereby, Donald W. Simpson and John Y. Glass, inventors; The Dow Chemical Company; November 10, 1970; Patent # 3,539,473
    Container, Charles E. Fitzgerald, inventor; The Dow Chemical Company; The Dow Chemical Company; August 12, 1968; Patent # 3, 520,441
  - Patents, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    Self-Cooking Disposable Food Packages, Milton S. Cohen, inventor; Batelle Development Corporation; November 9, 1971; Patent # 3,619,214
    Machine for Sealing Containers with Covers Molded from Synthetic Plastic Sheet, Horst Lowenthal, inventor; Schweizerische Industrie-Gesellschaft; November 9, 1971; Patent # 3, 618,293
    Apparatus for Forming Closures, Martin M. Sternau, inventor; W.R. Grace & Co.; November 23, 1971; Patent # 3, 621,637
    Continuous Motion Container Molding Machine, Bryant Edwards, inventor; Illinois Tool Works, Inc.; September 20, 1971; Patent # 3,605,192
    Vented Package, Robert F. Wescott, inventor; International Paper Company; October 19, 1971; Patent # 3,613,938
    Process for Pre-Expanding Polymer Beads, Richard H. Immel, inventor; Sinclair-Koppers Company; May 4, 1971; Patent # 3,577,360
    Method for Extruding Laminates, Douglas S. Chisholm, inventor; The Dow Chemical Company; January 19, 1971; Patent # 3,557,265
    Food Package, Daniel Bernhardt, inventor; April 20, 1971; Patent # 3,575,337
    Skin-Coated Article Formed of Foam Thermoplastic Material, Thomas W. Winstead, inventor; October 5, 1971; Patent # 3,610,509
    Forming unit for use with apparatus for forming and cutting three-dimensional plastic articles, Thomas W. Winstead, inventor; July 27, 1971; Patent # 3,594,868
    Cutting mechanism for use with apparatus for forming and cutting three-dimensional plastic articles, Thomas W. Winstead, inventor; July 7, 1970; Patent # 3,518,912
    Stacking and packaging unit for use with machine for continuously thermoforming plastic trays or the like, Thomas W. Winstead, inventor; June 22, 1971; Patent # 3,585,778
    Apparatus for Sealing Thin Walled Containers, Thomas Norman Gaunt and Edward Dodsworth, inventors; Plastona (John Waddington) Limited; February 29, 1972; Patent # 3,645,825
    Non-Toxic Stabilized Polyvinyl Chloride Products and Stabilizer Compositions, Carl Robert Gloskey, inventor; M&T Chemicals, Inc.; February 8, 1972; Patent # 3,640,947
    Plasticized Polyvinyl Chloride Film, Donatas Tijunlis and Edward A. Shriner, inventors; Union Carbide Corporation; February 1, 1972; Patent # 3,639,318
    Pellucid Halogen-Containing Resin Compositions, Kenneth C. Bergman and Thomas C. Jennings, inventors; Synthetic Products Company; February 1, 1972; Patent # 3,639,319
    Reentrant Forming Apparatus, Fred P. Brown and Howard H. Rohdin, inventors; Packaging Industries, Inc.; February 8, 1972; Patent # 3,640,668
    Folding Plastic Tray, Harford G. Goings, inventor; February 1, 1972; Patent # 3,638,849
    Liquid Containers, Uno Wingardh, inventor; Sprinter Pack AB; May 30, 1972; Patent # 3,666,088
    Cup, George A. Cheladze, inventor; Carthage Cup Company; May 30, 1972; Patent # Des. 233,704
    Cup, George A. Cheladze, inventor; Carthage Cup Company; May 30, 1972; Patent # Des. 233,703
    Stackable Insert Container for Axially Spaced Engaging Surfaces, Herbert J. Wanderer, inventor; Illinois Tool Works, Inc.; June 27, 1972; Patent # Re. 27,409
    Apparatus for Extruding a Skin-Covered, Foamed Thermoplastic; Thomas W. Winstead, inventor; August 19, 1969; Patent # 3,461,496
    Continuous Method of Extruding and Thermoforming Skin-Covered Foamed Thermoplastic Articles, Thomas W. Winstead, inventor; July 11, 1972; Patent # 3,676,537
    Continuous Apparatus for Extruding and Forming Thermoplastic Articles, Thomas W. Winstead, inventor; January 4, 1972, Patent # 3,632,266
  - Patents, 1974 (Box 1)
    Continuous Method of Manufacturing Articles from Foamed Thermoplastic Material; Thomas W. Winstead, inventor; January 29, 1974; Patent # 3,789,095
    Method of Molding a Latch Opening, Kurt G. Dahlberg, inventor; Thermo-Trim, Inc.; October 29, 1974; Patent # 3,845,187
    A Tool for Sealing a Container Such as a Cup, Bottle, Jar or the Like, Folke Evert Granseus and Ingvar Helmer Borgstrom, inventors; Aktiebolaget Platmanufaktur; November 26, 1974; Patent #3,849,971
    Method of Forming Foamed Plastic Sheets, Thomas W. Winstead, inventor; August 20, 1974; Patent # 3,830,900
    Extrusion Apparatus, Thomas W. Winstead, inventor; June 11, 1968; Patent # 3,387,328
    Continuous Process for Extruding Cellular Thermoplastics, Thomas W. Winstead, inventor; August 20, 1974; Patent # 3,830,901
  - Patents, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
    Apparatus for Molding Plastic Covers for Containers, Heinz Ruch, inventor; Albert Orbist October 28, 1975; Patent # 3,915,613
    Container for Cooking Food Therein, William P. Kane, inventor; E.I. du Pont de Nemours and Company; February 11, 1975; Patent # 3,865,302
    Vented Cavity Mold and Method of Thermoforming Using Such Mold; David Harris Berkebile, inventor; Patent # 1,428,328
    Integrity Indicator, Donald F. Halpern, inventor; Bio-Medical Sciences, Inc.; August 12, 1975; Patent # 3,899,295
    Thermoplastic Resin Composition Having High Transparency and High Impact Strength, Fumio Ide, Kazuo Kishida, Toshio Sakurai and Syoichi Kawakami, inventors; Mitsubishi Rayon Co., Ltd. and Nitto Chemical Industry Co., Ltd.; November 11, 1975; Patent # 3,919,157
    Simplified Process and Apparatus for the Production of Cups from a Foamed Thermoplastic Sheet, Jingo Seto, inventor; November 11, 1975; Patent # 3,919,368
    Lid for a Packaging Container or the Like, Paul Davis, inventor; November 18, 1975; Patent # Des. 237,689
    Cups for Holding Ingredients for Drinks, Robert H. Day, inventor; Illinois Tool Works, Inc.; December 23, 1975; Patent # 3,927,766
    Method for Forming Noncircular Thermoplastic Cupped Articles; Gerrit van der Gaag and Thomas C. Tomey; Shell Oil Company; December 30, 1975; Patent # 3,929,953
    Heat Sealing Apparatus, Fred Ascoli and Robert F. Hermann, inventors; Standard Container Company; February 10, 1976; Patent # 3,937,645
    Closuring Containers, Emile Raymond Vermeulen, inventor; Sidaplax N.V.; December 21, 1971; Patent # 3,628,301
    Shrink Film Capping Machine; Ernest Willvonseder; January 8, 1974; Patent # 3,783,582
    Method and Apparatus for Uniting Articles; Bryant Edwards, inventor; Illinois Tool Works, Inc.; February 6, 1968; Patent # 3,367,808
    Semi-Automatic Capping Machine; William J. Burke, inventor; Roll-O-Sheets, Inc.; February 8, 2012; Patent # 3,233,386
    Apparatus for Producing Packaged Product, Robert G. Carpenter, Richard G. King and Thomas W. Greaves, inventors; W.R. Grace & Co.; May 15, 1962; Patent # 3,034,271
    Apparatus for Feeding Heat Shrinkable Plastic Film and Capping Containers Therewith, Thomas E. Marion and Godfrey M. Priborksy, inventors; Maryland Cup Corporation; November 21, 1972; Patent # 3,703,066
    Thermoplastic Sealing Apparatus and Method, David R. Zelnick, inventor; Koehler-Dayton, Inc.; June 10, 1969; Patent # 3,449,183
    Method and Apparatus for Heat Shrink Capping Containers, William T. Doty, inventor; Maryland Cup Corporation; November 4, 1975; Patent # 3,916,602
    Apparatus for Making a Closure on a Container, Martin M. Sternau, inventor; W.R. Grace & Co.; October 31, 1972; Patent # 3,701,234
    Method for Blow Molding Foamed Walled Plastic Open Mouthed Containers, Granville J. Hahn, inventor; Cosden Oil & Chemical Company; February 17, 1976; Patent # 3,939,236
    Scrapless Forming of Plastic Articles, Ralph E. Ayres, Kenneth J. Cleereman and Walter E. Schrenk, inventors; The Dow Chemical Company; March 30, 1976; Patent # 3,947,204
    Packaging Container for a Razor or the Like, Carl H. Floren, inventor; The Gillette Company; May 18, 1976; Patent # Des. 239,920
    Lid, Clarence T. Brewer, inventor; Solo Cup Company; May 4, 1976; Patent # 3,583,596
    Close Nesting, Tamperproof Container Closure, Stephen W. Amberg and Rodney E. Ludder, inventors; Owens-Illinois, Inc.; May 11, 1976; Patent # 3,955,699
    Sealed Container, James B. Swett, inventor; Dart Industries, Inc.; May 18, 1976; Patent # 3,957,097
    Container Closure, Elmer E. Kress, inventor; July 7, 1976; Patent # 240,595
    Covered Container for Serving Food with Combination Ventilation and Finger Holes, Nicholas D. Commisso, inventor; Mobil Oil Corporation; May 11, 1976; Patent # 3,955,710
    Food Packaging Tray, Thomas H. White, inventor; Rubbermaid Industrial Products Corporation; July 27, 1976; Patent # 240,714
    Tamper Indicator Tape, Lew W. Cornell, inventor; Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing Company; February 3, 1976; Patent # 3,935,960
    Apparatus for Folding Container Rims, Gaylord William Brown, inventor; October 21, 1975; Patent # 3,914,102
    Foam Package for Breakfast Foods, Donald K. Jewell, inventor; Restaurant Technology, Inc.; July 13, 1976; Patent # 3,968,921
    Straw Dispenser, Stanley W. Peva, Jr., inventor; Austin-Gordon Design, Inc.; July 13, 1976; Patent # 3,968,901
    Foam Bead Bottom Plastic Cup and Method of Making Same, Clifford Clayton Goehring, inventor; American Can Company; January 6, 1976; Patent # 3,931,378
    Method of Making Nestable Foamed Plastic Cups, Ilie Mila Belivakici, Clifford Clayton Goehring, James Allan Wachtel, William Joseph Lahm and Carl Richard Storms, inventors; American Can Company; January 6, 1976; Patent # 3,931,380
    Insulative Packaging Device, Wayne L. Congleton, inventor; Dolco Packaging Corporation; January 20, 1976; 3,933,295
    Plastic Container, Algis Steven Andrulionis, inventor; Polysar Plastics, Inc.; January 27, 1976; Patent # 3,934,749
  - Patents, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
    Pumped Injection of Gas for Making Foamed Plastic, James W. Hendry, inventor; Ex-Cell-O Corporation; August 23, 1977; Patent # 4,043,715
    Polyethylene Terephthalate/Terpolymer Blends, Film Sheets, and Articles Made Using Such Blends, and Method of Making Trays Using Such Sheets, Frederick W. Gander, Ernard F, Hoegger, William P. Kane, inventors; E.I. Du Pont de Nemours and Company; April 26, 1977; Patent # 4,020,126
    Apparatus for Making Hollow Molded Products, Arthur J. Griner and Daniel Anthony Koppa, inventors; Nabisco, Inc.; July 26, 1977; Patent # 4,038,007
    Apparatus for Making Hollow Molded Products, Arthur J. Griner and Daniel Anthonu Koppa, inventors; Nabisco, Inc.; July 26, 1977; Patent # 4,038,016
    Sheet Support Apparatus, Gaylord William Brown, inventor; Sweetheart Plastics, Inc.; July 18, 1978; Patent # 4,101,252
    Laminated Material of Thermoplastic Synthetic Material, Process of Making and Container Closed Therewith, Barbara Geppert and Kurt Huth, inventors; Bellaplast, GmbH; July 18, 1978; Patent # 4,101,047
  - Patents, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    Nestable Containers, Daniel R. Kalata and Henry Huston, inventors; Owens-Illinois, Inc.; July 26, 1977; Patent # Re. 29, 320
    Apparatus for Pre-Expanding and Molding Expandable Thermoplastic Polymer Particles, Stuart B. Smith, inventor; Foster Grant Co., Inc.; November 29, 1977; Patent # 4,060,354
    Apparatus for the Manufacture of Thin-Walled Shaped Articles of Thermoplastic Material, Alfons W. Thiel and Hans Hell, inventors; Bellaplast GmbH; August 8, 1978; Patent # 4,105,386
    Method and Indicator for Detecting the Loss of Integrity of a Package, Donald F. Halpern, inventor; Bio-Medical Sciences Inc.; July 4, 1978; Patent # 4,098,577
    Sterile Package, Syed M.H. Zaidi, inventor; Paper Manufacturers Company; April 15, 1979; Patent # 4,197,947
    Apparatus for Heating a Food Item, Albert E. Colato and Jerome L. Formo, inventors; Anchor Hocking Corporation; August 1, 1978; Patent # 4,103,736
    The Winstead Patents: Analysis of Content and Coverage, Terrell C. Birch; 19 page typescript summary; July 18, 1977
  - Patents, 1979-1987 (Box 2)
    Tamper-Proof Closure and Method of Making Same, Gaylord Brown, inventor; Sweetheart Plastic, Inc.; June 24, 1980; Patent # 4,209,101
    Method and Apparatus for Thermoforming Thermoplastic Foam Articles, Donald W. Myers and Samantha L. Vivlamore, inventors; Mobil Oil Corporation; December 16, 1980; Patent # 4,239,727
    Method for the Continuous Formation of Biaxially Oriented Thermoplastic Materials and Forming Articles Therefrom by Intermittent Forming Means Interfaced Therewith, Thomas W. Winstead, inventor; Maryland Cup Corporation; December 22, 1981; Patent # 4,307,049
    Tilt Indicator for Shipping Containers, Ralph R. Mendelson, inventor; July 20, 1982; Patent # 4,340,008
    Non-Spill Drink-Through Lid, William A. Dart and Kenneth B. Dart, inventors; Dart Container Corporation; November 1, 1983; Patent # 4,412,629
    Container Closure Alignment Device, Robert H.C. M. Daenen, inventor; Dart Industries, Inc.; November 1, 1983; Patent # 4,412,630
    Spill Resistant Disposable Paper Drinking Cup, William C. La Fever, inventor; November 1, 1983; Patent # 4,412,644
    Method for Forming a Cup-Like Container, Carl Arndt and Martin Mueller, inventors; Owens-Illinois Inc.; May 31, 1983; Patent # 4,386,044
    Thermoformable Polymer Blend Composition, Michael R. Grancio, David F. Stewart and John F. Cass, inventors; Sweetheart Plastics, Inc.; May 31, 1983; Patent # 4,386,188
    Thermoformable Polymer Blend Composition Comprising Styrene Polymer, Olefin Polymer and Block Copolymer, Michael C. Grancio, David F. Stewart and John F. Cass, inventors; Sweetheart Plastics, Inc.; May 31, 1983; Patent # 4,386,187
    Apparatus for the Continuous Formation of Biaxially Oriented Thermoplastic Materials and Forming Articles Therefrom by Intermittent Forming Means Interfaced Therewith, Thomas W. Winstead, inventor; Maryland Cup Coproration; May 24, 1983; Patent # 4,348,836
    Tuck and Nest Method and Apparatus, Gaylord Brown, inventor; Sweetheart Plastic Inc.; May 24, 1983; Patent # 4,384,439
    Edible Food Containers and the Method of Coating Said Containers, Irving H. Rubenstein and Herbert M. Bank, inventors; Maryland Cup Corporation; June 28, 1983; Patent # 4,390,553
    Methods and Apparatus for Curling Lips about the Open Mouths of Stacked Thermoplastic Containers, Albert W. Arends and Ronald E. Henke, inventors; Leesona Corporation; July 5,1983; Patent # 4,391,768
    Thermoformable Polymer Blend Composition Comprising Styrene Polymer, Olefin Polymer and Block Copolymer, Michael R. Grancio, David F. Stewart and John F. Cass, inventors; Sweetheart Plastics, Inc.; May 31, 1983; Patent # 4,386,187